Guide to the Upton Sinclair collection, 1952-1978
Department of Special Collections
Upton Sinclair collection,
1952-1978
Special Collections M0327
Namikawa, Ryo, 1905-
10 v.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Ryo Namikawa, 1978.
Scope and Content
Two volumes containing letters, postcards, clippings, and typed poems from Upton Sinclair and Mary Craig Sinclair to Ryo Namikawa. Also includes 8 volumes of Upton Sinclair's works translated into Japanese by Namikawa with a holograph note in Namikawa's hand.
Container List
- Namikawa Gift-list:
  - 1. Two volumes of Upton Sinclair and Mary Craig Sinclair letters, postcards, clippings and typed poems with manuscript corrections.
  - 2. Eight volumes of Upton Sinclair's works translated into Japanese by Dr. Namikawa, all with a holograph note by Dr. Namikawa.
    - 1. Upton Sinclair presents William Fox.
    - 2. & 3. A world to win. Vols. 1 and 2.
    - 4. Lanny Budd. I World's end
    - 5. Lanny Budd. II Between two worlds
    - 6. Lanny Budd. III Dragon's teeth
    - 7. Lanny Budd. IV Wide is the gate.
    - 8. Lanny Budd. V Presidential Agent.
- THE LETTERS FROM UPTON SINCLAIR TO RYO NAMIKAWA (VOL.III)
  - 1. 2 photographs of translator Ryo Namikawa (1978)
  - 2. Cover written by Sinclair (1952)
  - 3. Text of letter from Einstein to Sinclair
  - 4. ALS to Namikawa (Dec 8 52)
  - 5. Cover written by Sinclair (Aug 18 52)
  - 6. Cover written by Sinclair (Aug 18 52)
  - 7. Cover written by Sinclair (Aug 52)
  - 8. Text of Poem by Mary Craig Sinclair with Japanese notes (1952)
  - 9. Text of Poem by Mary Craig Sinclair (1952)
  - 10. Letter from Mary Craig Sinclair, handwritten and signed (Aug 52)
  - 11. Cover typed from Sinclair (1952)
  - 12. TLS from Sinclair re: Lanny (Oct 4 52)
  - 13. Cover written by Sinclair (July 10 52)
  - 14. Cover of The New Leader featuring Sinclair (June 30 52)
  - 15. Page of Sinclair's article (in The New Leader?)
  - 16. ALS to Namikawa
  - 17. Cover written by Sinclair (Oct 2 52)
  - 18. Text of letter from B.W. Huebsch to Sinclair re: Lanny Budd (Sept 22 52)
  - 19. Cover typed from Sinclair (Oct 9 52)
  - 20. Cover written by Sinclair (Aug 52)
  - 21. Cover written by Sinclair (July 18 52)
  - 22. First page of An Open Letter to Stalin,:The New Leader Page 2
  - 23. (Same as Item #15) second page of An Open Letter to Stalin
  - 24. Page entitled Books by Upton Sinclair
  - 25. ALS to Namikawa
  - 26. Cover written by Sinclair (Dec 31 52)
  - 27. Text of letter from Frederic Morton to Sinclair re: Lanny Budd Flies Again (Nov 5 52)
  - 28. Review Upton Sinclair on Christ, Page 21 Writers and Writing (Nov 10 52)
  - 29. ALS to Namikawa re: payment for The Return of Lanny Budd (Dec 31 52)
  - 30. Cover written by Sinclair (Mar 13 53)
  - 31.-32, Typed proposal for printing Return of L.B. by Sinclair
  - 33. ALS to Namikawa re: date of Japanese publication (53)
  - 34. ALS to Namikawa re: gifts to Sinclair (Aug 15 54)
  - 35. Cover written by Sinclair (June 54)
  - 36. Newspaper article Distinguished Novelist asks: When Is a Communist? by Sinclair in Brooklyn Eagle.
  - 37. Cover written by U.S. to R.N. (May 29 54)
  - 38. Newspaper article Red World Blueprints Upset by True Liberals ( Mar 31 54by U.S.)
  - 39. Cover written by U.S. to R.N. (May 29 54)
  - 40. Magazine article Art vs. Propaganda by U.S. (May 10 54)
  - 41. TLS from U.S. to R.N. re: wife and Didymus story (July 29 54)
  - 42. TLS from U.S. to R.N. re: wife and The Enemy Had It Too (June 3 54)
  - 43. Cover typed from U.S. to R.N. (Apr 29 54)
  - 44. TLS from U.S. to R.N. re: Mental Radio (April 28 54)
  - 45. Cover typed from U.S. to R.N. (Oct 54)
  - 46. TLS from U.S. to R.N. re: What Didymus Did (Oct 25 54)
  - 47. ALS from U.S. to R.N. re: Cup of Fury (Dec 26 55)
  - 48. Cover typed from U.S. to R.N. (Jan 10 55)
  - 49. Text of letters re: What Didymus Did from Einstein and Jung
  - 50. TLS with note from U.S. to R.N. re: Doctor Fist )Jan 8 55)
  - 51. Cover written by U.S. to R.N. (Feb 21 55)
  - 52. 2 clippings: Time of Grandeur from Waco, Texas News Tribune (Feb 16 54)and Communist Tactics Create Confused Thinking in U.S. (May 20 54)both by Sinclair
  - 53. Clipping Drinking and Driving Don's Mix.. by Sinclair (0 54)
  - 54. ALS from U.S. to R.N.
  - 55. Cover written by U.S. to R.N.
  - 56. 2 page text for newspaper article, The Seamy Side of Social Drinking by Sinclair (for release Dec 18 54)
  - 57. Cover written by U.S. to R.N. (April 56)
  - 58-60 Article Einstein and Reflections by Sinclair
  - 61. Cover written by U.S. to R.N. (April 27 56)
  - 62. Newspaper review of Cup of Fury with note from Sinclair
  - 63. 2 magazine clippings by Sinclair from Time (April 30 56)re: alcohol. (one is pasted in upside down)
- THE LETTERS FROM UPTON SINCLAIR TO RYO NAMIKAWA (VOL IV)
  - 1. Copy of typed letter from John Haynes Holmes to Mrs. Upton Sinclair (Jan 2 51)
  - 2-4 TLS from Mary Craig Sinclair to RN re: radio programs with Japanese note. (Feb 13 52)
  - 5-12 Typed letter re radio programs by Sinclair with note and signature.
  - 13. Telegram between US and RN re: permission for extracts 8/22/52
  - 14. Cover written by US to RN and note by RN (1978)
  - 15-19 Copy of message for Kaizo by US, with note by RN (53)